



ʃ Hi, I'm Andrew M Westling, a software engineer in Brooklyn, NY.

I'm a designer-turned-engineer. I was going to be an architect, but then I got distracted by the web. For the last 9 years, I've been working as a **front end engineer**.

These days, I build web apps. My favorite things to work on are **design systems**, and front end features for TypeScript and JavaScript applications. I'm handy with React, Next.js, and Tailwind, among many other tools. I also like to think about how processes scale, and how teams can work together more harmoniously.

hi@andrewwestling.com

Experience

Forte, Senior Software Engineer

July 2022–March 2023, remote (New York City)

First engineering hire. Feature development, setting up tools and culture. Forte is a purposebuilt music education platform for teachers and students.

- From scratch: I set up Forte's Next.js application from scratch; I chose tools and workflows to set us up for quick iteration; established a component library to keep things consistent
- Built features: I built the first iteration of various customer-facing features for Forte's marketplace: Teacher Profiles; Certified Institutions; Invitations and Sign Up; Teacher Ratings and Reviews; "Switch Role" functionality; etc.
- UX/Product Architecture: I got to inform the UX, product flow, and overall architecture of a multi-role marketplace application
- **Migration**: We migrated to Next.js from a prior AWS Amplify application

Tools we used: React, TypeScript, Next.js, GraphQL, Prisma, Tailwind, Flowbite, Ladle, Vercel

Monograph, Senior Front End Engineer

April 2021–June 2022, remote (New York City)

Design system and feature development for Monograph's applications. Monograph makes tools to help architecture firms manage their projects, budgets, and tasks.

- **Design systems**: I built components for Monograph's component library; also wrote documentation and set up workflows between Figma and the codebase
- **Features**: I built assorted customer-facing features: Team Directory; filter functionality for Monograph Resource; Settings UI; etc.
- <u>"Glue" work</u>: A lot of hard-to-quantify things like process documentation, choosing tools, configuration, code reviews, data migration scripts, customer support collaboration, bug triaging, etc.

Tools we used: React, TypeScript, Stitches, Figma, Storybook, GraphQL, Rails, Vercel, Heroku, Linear

Better.com, Software Engineer

July 2018-April 2021, New York City

Design system and feature development for Better's loan origination platform. Better.com is a mortgage lender.

- **Design systems**: I was one of the first members of Better's Design Systems team; we built libraries to empower our engineering teams to build consistent and clean UIs
- **Features**: I built assorted borrower-facing features: redisclosure service; "required assets and buffer" logic; authentication/session expiration; UX for uploading a competitor's loan estimate; loan overview page; etc.
- **Integrations**: I worked on integrations with sales and marketing tools (call scheduling, A/B testing, etc.)

Tools we used: React, TypeScript, Theme UI, Storybook, Ember, Node.js, SCSS, Optimizely, Segment

Architizer, Software Engineer

September 2015-June 2018, New York City

Full-stack and front end feature development and infrastructure maintenance for Architizer's platform to help architects find building products.

• Component libraries: I established and maintained a UI component system to speed up

feature development, and improve collaboration with designers

- **Features**: I built internal- and external-facing features: a private messaging interface; directory interfaces to Solr search indexes; etc.
- Integrations: Extended integrations with external tools for analytics, error logging, marketing, and customer support
- Infrastructure: Optimized frontend infrastructure to speed up deployment and improve test coverage
- Tech debt: Pruned AWS resources to reduce costs, and refactored stale application code

Tools we used: React, Next.js, Storybook, styled-components, AngularJS, SCSS, Django, Solr, Segment, Node.js, CircleCl, AWS, Docker, gulp

EyeCue Lab, Software Engineer

October 2014-August 2015, Portland, Oregon

Internship-to-hire. Consultancy/agency setting. Built marketing pages and full-stack features for web applications and client projects.

Epicodus

July 2014–October 2014, Portland, Oregon

Code school. Learned Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and other tools. Attained internship-to-hire with EyeCue Lab after Epicodus.

Apple, AppleCare Advisor

June 2013–May 2014, remote (Eugene, Oregon)

Technical phone support and customer service for macOS products while I completed my degree.

Tools I use

I have experience with (and would be happy to work with) the following tools:

JS/TS: TypeScript, React, Next.js, GraphQL, Apollo, Prisma, Jest, Ember.js, Node.js, AngularJS,

webpack

UI: Tailwind, Flowbite, Ladle, Storybook, Stitches, Radix, Theme UI, styled-components, MDX, SCSS, Tachyons

General: Vercel, Heroku, Rails, nginx, Docker, AWS, Segment, CircleCI, Django, Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Linear

Education

Bachelor of Architecture (B.Arch), University of Oregon, 2014

Last updated: 2023-05-15